# **Tauseef Ibne Mamun**

tmamun@mtu.edu +1 (857)-574-9931 https://tmamun.netlify.app

407 Shelden Avenue, Apt 9, Houghton, Michigan, 49931

## **SUMMARY**

Ph.D. student with specialized training in both *human-computer interaction* and *behavioral psychology*. Have a *strong programming* background. Experience in human factors analysis (*qualitative* and *quantitative*) and executing *usability* studies mainly in software and rail warning systems.

### **Research Tools/Methods**

- Usability Evaluation (in-vehicular warning system, explainable AI system).
- In-field semi-structured user/driver interview.
- Autonomous driving behavior analysis in the driving simulator.
- Data interpretation using advanced statistical modeling.

## **EDUCATION**

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Ph.D. Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors

Expected May 2023

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

Artificial Intelligence in Healthcare Certificate

2021

Michigan Technological University | Houghton, MI

**MS Applied Cognitive Science and Human Factors** 

2019 - 2021

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

**BS Computer Science & Engineering** 

2011 - 2015

## **EXPERIENCES**

Michigan Technological University, Cognitive and Learning Sciences | Houghton, MI

# **Research Assistant**

2019 - Present

# Tasks:

- Social media data analysis (qualitative data) and human behavior analysis in autonomous driving while giving user-centric explanations from social media for human-Al collaboration.
- Designing novel explanation methods for the human-Al team.
- Developing computational models for different scenarios, e.g., pandemic human travel patterns.
- Behavioral analysis of drivers in rail crossings through statistical models and semi-structured interviews;
  also determining the usability of new systems in rail crossings.
  - Working/Worked with Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and Federal Railroad Administration on different research projects.

Mighty Egg Technologies | Canada/Bangladesh

# **Programmer Analyst**

2015 - 2018

Software deployment in Amazon Web Service,

Digital Ocean, Heroku.

# Tasks:

- Database Design & API development.
- Web and Mobile App Development.

### **Programming Expertise**

R, Python, C, C++, Java, PHP, Ruby, PEBL

Git: GitHub (https://github.com/tm012)

### FEATURED LEADERSHIP ROLES

- Vice President at Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology's Computer Science & Engineering Society
- Vice President at Bangladeshi Student Association at Michigan Technological University
  2020 2021

## **INTERESTS**

Photography | App Development | Video and Photo Editing